[engine starts, revving]
[Jerry] Weird. Wild. Odd.
This is a 1964 Studebaker Avanti...
Avanti.
...in red. Interior: black vinyl.
Studebaker was an American car company
that lasted until about 1967.
The name tells you
everything you need to know.
Studebaker.
They used to make
cars like the Lark, the Hawk.
They like birds, these people.
And making sure their car
can go through a puddle.
And hit some straw.
They didn't do well,
so in a last ditch,
Hail Mary effort to save their business,
they asked design genius Raymond Loewy
to make them a sports car,
which he did in a 40-day crash program
somewhere on the outskirts of Las Vegas.
He created the entire concept
in eight days on one condition.
Studebaker was not allowed to change
one aspect of his original design.
Of course not. Look at this man.
He's got a mustache,
two hankies, and a tie bar.
You gonna argue with him
about how something should look?
It is the Avanti.
People loved it. They wanted to buy it.
But when they came in the showroom,
it wasn't there.
Studebaker couldn't figure out
how to build enough of them
and they collapsed anyway.
Nice try.
[tires screech]
It is also the favorite car of
my wonderfully funny guest today,
Mr. J.B. Smoove.
But he has never been in one, never owned
one, never even had a ride in one.
But "Avanti" means "Let's go!" So, we are.
[phone ringing]
-[J.B.] Hello?
-[Jerry] J.B.
[Jerry] J.S.
You won't believe
what I got for you today.
[J.B.] I'm hoping you have
what I think you have.
[Jerry] All your dreams
come true today, J.B.
[J.B.] I can't wait!
I'm tingly! I'm tingly!
I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians In Cars Getting Coffee.
Oh, this is beautiful.
-Comedy brother.
-Comedy.
This comedy gold.
They always say comedy gold.
Is there a silver and bronze also?
That might as well be garbage.
Never even heard people
-use the term...
-No.
...comedy bronze or comedy silver.
-We don't trade in that.
-Always gold.
Always gold.
This is probably the nicest
Studebaker Avanti in the world.
Are you kidding me?
You know what I love about this Avanti?
It mixes European styling
with American ingenuity.
And this "S" also stands for "Smoove!"
You can't beat this!
Look at this steering wheel,
these little grips.
Now here's my favorite feature.
Are you ready?
This is for your lady.
How much would your wife go nuts for that?
Jerry, I'm telling you,
this is like Christmas.
-Your birthday. Yeah.
-A car should feel like Christmas.
[J.B.] Gonna tell you something.
A bloody nose can get you out of anything.
If you carry a handkerchief
with red dye on it,
you go, "Oh!"
You tap your nose a few times.
Like that.
You pull that handkerchief out,
you don't let them see the red.
If you go like this,
they will panic with you.
And you go like this.
-"Excuse me, I have a bloody nose."
-That's so funny.
You are excused from anything.
Court, you get pulled over,
by the police, pull you over.
-Right.
-Everybody respects a bloody nose, Jerry.
People who love J.B.,
-love J.B.
-Yeah.
Do you feel comfortable
calling yourself by your name?
I love putting myself in the third person.
-Yeah.
-I love it, man.
-So, you're a fan also of your--
-You gotta be a fan.
-Yeah.
-Gotta be a fan.
[Jerry] When you have a set
that you don't like,
what do you do
to make yourself feel better?
I'll stop by and get
a pint of Häagen-Dazs.
Yeah, I've done that. Mint Chip.
You're a Mint Chip guy.
Know what? You look like a Mint Chip guy.
Mine is Butter Pecan.
But I don't chew any of the pecans
until I finish the ice cream.
-But you know how--
-Boy, people are so strange.
So, you save the pecan for last,
even though there's no way
a pecan can follow an ice cream.
If you were putting together a show,
the ice cream is gonna close the show.
The pecan is gonna open.
I like how you think like a stand-up.
-That's my life.
-The ice cream is the opener.
Ice cream always closes.
Nobody wants to follow ice cream.
Most and very important to me about a car
is the actuation of
all the knobs and levers.
I want you to feel
putting this in reverse, how nice it is.
Hold that button. Yeah, and then...
Isn't that nice? The sound too, I like.
-Yeah. Yeah.
-A nice click sound. Listen.
You know when it clicks, it's locked in.
Here's another thing, J.B.,
the door notches.
Watch it goes up one,
and look at how wide it goes,
-even wider, really easy.
-Oh!
How do you like that?
Know what I do with my car? I baby my car.
A lot of people use, uh,
towels and rags to wash their car.
-Know what I wash my car with?
-What?
Lingerie.
[exhales]
Ladies' lingerie.
I soap it up, and I'll wash my car.
Know why? 'Cause it's very delicate.
The thing that makes me
the most uncomfortable about this
is that you have lowered your voice
and you're whispering this to me.
-I'm setting the mood.
-I know.
That's making me uncomfortable, too.
[inaudible]
-Oh.
-Man, that's good.
I lived in the projects in Mount Vernon.
-In the projects?
-Yeah, man.
I lost a lot of friends.
I got friends who didn't
make it past 16 years old,
so, you know, it's a great city.
Hold on a second.
That sentence does not flow.
"I lost a lot of friends
before the age of 16..."
-Yeah.
-"It's a great city."
[J.B.] You know what I love?
When people laugh at the premise
before you even get to the punchline.
-It's the greatest.
-And you say to yourself, "Oh, you wait."
When the premise gets something,
that's the greatest thing in comedy.
I had a bit about chopsticks.
The beginning of the premise was,
"I see the Chinese are hanging
in there with the chopsticks..."
[both laughing]
I haven't even started the bit.
Now let me tell you what lazy is.
The straw.
You're two inches away from what you want.
That much space
between the glass and the straw.
Do you need that help?
Sometimes you can't find it. Like...
Nobody looks good trying to get a straw.
-You try to talk to people like...
-Yeah.
What's it for?
Is it people think the glass is dirty?
You're drinking what's in the glass.
I think at some point,
the zombie apocalypse is gonna happen.
Now, just to refresh my memory,
the zombies,
they're dead and now they're back?
-They're undead.
-And you like this.
Yeah. Come back from the dead.
But I do...
[both laughing]
-So what's your favorite zombie show?
-Walking Dead, man.
I've never seen that.
-Jerry.
-I'm sorry.
-If you don't jump on Walking Dead...
I'm almost disgusted
that you have not yet--
-I know, I know.
-People have told you, right?
You're not the first person to be upset
with me for not watching their show.
-Their show.
-This is another thing
we need to stop doing to each other.
-I cannot believe--
-I can't believe you missed The Grifters.
-What's wrong with you?
-"What's wrong with you?"
That bothers me more
than the zombies trying to eat my brain.
I worked at this perfume company,
man, for a few years.
This guy taught me how to mix perfumes.
I knew everything.
I knew the ingredients.
Lavenders and rosemarys.
I could have been a perfumer.
You know? Very easily.
You look like a guy
who started out in the perfume industry.
You look like you're still in it, frankly.
I used to be a waiter.
I was doing stand-up for free at night.
And I would work as a waiter
from 10:00 a.m. to 2:00 p.m.
I always did the lunch rush.
And a couple of times, J.B.,
I walked up to a table
and they looked up at me and said,
"I saw you on stage last night. I thought
those were professional comedians."
And I would just have to go,
"Well, not yet."
[both laughing]
I love that.
But that prepares you, though.
You were dealing with people directly.
Who's not dealing with people directly?
-Is that a real bow tie?
-It's a real bow tie.
It's beautifully tied. That knot is tight.
Have you ever heard of
the Bow Tie Exchange Program?
-No.
-Let me tell you about this world.
If I have my bow tie on, right?
Suppose another guy was sitting there.
He had a fancy bow tie.
If you like my bow tie
and I like your bow tie,
sometimes we'll meet,
and I'll say, "Hey, nice tie."
Say, "Yeah, I like yours too."
It's a certain energy
and a look we give each other,
and what happens is you untie your tie,
he unties his tie, and you exchange ties.
This sounds like the way
homosexuality was conducted in the '50s.
-Now, J.B., the "J" stands for "Jerry."
-Jerry.
-We are the Jerrys.
-Okay?
I think all Jerrys
look a little bit alike.
And I would say further,
I think you and I look a little bit alike.
We do. I agree.
Absolutely agree.
-Really?
-Yeah!
This fly is just ruining my life.
I once saw a short film that was--
somebody attempted
to make the point of view of a fly.
That's a wild ride.
If you could get a camera small enough,
and I bet you someday they will
have a camera they can mount on a fly.
-Need permission from a fly to put it on.
-You can hold him down.
Yeah, but he still has to... He may...
Know what I mean?
It may be uncomfortable.
I don't care.
[laughing]
[Jerry] Thank you.
-"I don't care."
-I'm running this thing, not the fly.
I love bees.
It's like human society,
but they don't have the problems
of human society.
The worker bee doesn't
look at the drone and go,
-"I should be doing that."
-You're right.
[both laughing]
I used to sell fire extinguishers
door-to-door,
which is the most terrible...
Selling fire extinguishers door-to-door
is an art.
For sure. It's one of the highest arts.
-What was your most effective fear tactic?
-I mean, it's creepy.
You open the door, I lean slightly...
just to peek in a little bit.
Then I lean back up to see
if I can see anything in the background
or hear kids.
-Good.
-Hear kids...
If you're a fire extinguisher salesman,
the best thing to see on the floor
-is toys.
-Is toys.
I imagine there's a lot of "God forbid"
in that pitch.
Oh, my God.
"God forbid,
but if that happens, Mr. Johnson..."
Yeah. So I gotta get in your house,
number one.
Once I get in,
I'll start doing my demonstration.
So I get in the house, I said,
"I'm gonna show you a demonstration."
I took my pan out, tear the paper up.
I light it up. [mimics explosion]
But Jerry, you gotta realize
I must have done 100 demonstrations.
I didn't get a new sample
fire extinguisher for testing.
-Oh, no.
-So...
Oh, no.
Jerry, Jerry,
I started a fire in a man's house.
I went to use this fire extinguisher,
it would not work.
That's a great story.
"How did the house burn down?"
"A fire extinguisher salesman."
-Hi.
-[woman] It's my birthday today.
Happy birthday!
-What's your name?
-Eighty-five. Jeannie.
Jeannie. Happy birthday.
-Eighty-five. God bless you.
-Eighty-five!
Did you hear about the two prostitutes
talking to one another
and one says, "Do you smoke after sex?"
She says, "I don't know, I never looked."
[both laughing]
That's a good one.
You should put on some brighter colors
on an 85th birthday.
Are you in the Bow Tie Exchange Program?
Do you want to exchange your bow tie
for her death pendant?
-I would love to.
-No, no, no.
My pendant is very old.
-I love that...
-Really?
Is that from the Titanic?
[inaudible]
[Jerry] Look at the sheep.
They're all looking at us
like we're looking at them.
They're going, "Look at those two guys."
This is where
they got the idea of Jar Jar Binks.
They had one good joke
in seven Star Wars movies,
when Jar Jar Binks says, "Exsqueeze me."
That was the best line.
Do you think this looks like you and me?
It's very close, matter of fact.
[both laughing]
[J.B.] You ever been to a bathroom
with a trough?
-Yes.
-That's something that I don't like.
I don't like it either.
Even though you don't really care
what happens to your pee
once it leaves you.
You don't care.
But still, I don't want it joining
everybody else's pee,
right here, right now.
[Jerry] I'm happy to be talking to you
today as a fellow automobile person.
What is it about driving a car?
I mean, I just love turning this wheel
and then the car turns!
-People like going places, man.
-Right.
But a classic car enhances that even more.
[Jerry] Yes, it does, because
there's a little time traveling.
[J.B.] Little time traveling.
-Right now it's 1964.
-Right.
Sure, I can't drink out of every
water fountain right now, but it's 1964!
A certain thing I don't trust
getting from people...
A delivery of milk from the milk company
to my house, to my porch.
-I don't trust...
-But they refrigerate it.
If the person delivering the milk to me
was a cow...
Ah.
I'd rather have the cow himself
pull up and milk himself
into the glass and give it to me.
I'll tell ya, a cow milking himself
might not be the first thing
you want to see in the morning.
[J.B. laughing]
Let's take the sound pack
out of your pocket.
It's out of my pocket
because the last thing I want to do
is go on a drug deal
and they ask me if I'm wired,
and I say, "No, I'm not wired."
Say, "What's that?"
[both laughing]